i'm jake o'neill
我是杰克·奥尼尔
creator of animagraphs
动画创作者
and this is the lockheed sr-71 blackbird
这是洛克希德SR-71黑鸟
the sr-71 entered service in the united states air force
sr-71进入美国空军服役
in nineteen sixty six as a reconnaissance aircraft
1966年作为侦察机
or in other words
或者换句话说
a spy plane
侦察机
it doesn't carry bombs or have onboard guns
它不携带炸弹或机载枪支
its main defense against enemy
它对敌人的主要防御
action is altitude and speed
动作是高度和速度
which made it essentially invulnerable
这使得它基本上无懈可击
sustaining Mach three point two
保持3.2马赫
that is three point two times the speed of sound
是音速的3.2倍
which roughly correlates to about two
这大致与大约两个相关
thousand two hundred plus miles per hour at
每小时一千二百多英里
altitudes up to eighty five thousand feet
高度高达八万五千英尺
no sr-71 was ever shot down to evade
没有SR-71被击落以躲避
missiles or hostile aircraft
导弹或敌机
if they could even reach the sr-71's altitude
如果他们能到达SR-71的高度
pilots simply outran them
飞行员只是跑得比他们快
every part of this masterpiece is
这部杰作的每一部分都是
designed for its mission goals
为其使命目标而设计
let's have a general look around the plane to get an idea
让我们看看飞机周围的情况
of how those goals translate into the physical design of
这些目标如何转化为物理设计
things before we zoom in on the finer details of each system
在我们放大每个系统的更精细细节之前
the blackbird is a relatively large airplane compared to
黑鸟是相对较大的飞机相比
other fighter or reconnaissance craft of the era
时代的其他战斗机或侦察机
flying at untouchable altitudes and
在不可触及的高度飞行
speeds simply requires a lot of fuel
速度只是需要大量的燃料
two thirds of the fuselage is occupied by cylindrical
机身的三分之二被圆柱形占据
fuel tanks and any usable space in the wings for a total
燃料箱和机翼上的任何可用空间总计
capacity of twelve thousand two hundred and nineteen
容量一万二千二百一十九
point two gallons weighing in at around eighty thousand
2加仑重约8万
two hundred and eighty five pounds of fuel
285磅燃料
a pair of powerful jet engines are
一对强大的喷气发动机
secured into the wings at both sides
固定在两侧的机翼上
a substantial portion of this compartment called the
这个隔间的很大一部分叫做
nacelle is dedicated to large movable inlet cones
机舱专用于大型可移动入口锥
called spikes which as we'll see later are critical
叫做尖峰，我们稍后会看到这是至关重要的。
for the sr-71's supersonic speed capabilities
SR-71的超音速能力
a row of flaps along the back of the wing called
机翼后面的一排襟翼叫做
ailerons and rudders perched atop each nacelle make
每个机舱上的副翼和方向舵
up the flight control surfaces for the plane
在飞机的飞行控制面上
heading to the front
走向前线
there are two cockpits for the pilot and
飞行员有两个驾驶舱
reconnaissance systems officer respectively
侦察系统军官
equipment bays surround the cockpits and can be fitted
驾驶舱周围有设备舱，可以安装
with an array of components depending on the mission
根据任务有一系列组件
as well as the removable nose section
还有可拆卸的鼻子部分
now let's get into the details starting
现在让我们从细节开始
with the exterior aerodynamics
与外部空气动力学
the engines appear to be tilted
引擎似乎倾斜了
slightly downwards on the ground
在地面上稍微向下
at cruising altitude and speed they're closer to
在巡航高度和速度下，它们更接近
level with a fuselage and wing designed to sit at six
与机身和机翼设计成6平
degrees positive rotation or angle of attack
正旋转或迎角
to carry sufficient fuel
携带足够的燃料
equipment and personnel
设备和人员
the fuselage and nose of the plane is quite long
飞机的机身和机头相当长
the Blackbird has a Delta wing design
黑鸟有三角翼设计
so called for its triangular shape
所谓的三角形
like a Greek Delta character
就像希腊三角洲的角色
exceeding the speed of sound or going
超过音速的
supersonic as the sr-71 was designed to do
超音速就像SR-71设计的那样
means pushing hard against air molecules
意味着用力推空气分子
air molecules are real physical things
空气分子是真实存在的物质
bonded together in a sort of elastic mesh
以一种弹性网粘合在一起
and sound happens when those molecules ram into each
当这些分子撞击每个分子时，就会产生声音
other to eventually physically jiggle your eardrum
其他最终物理抖动你的耳膜
the spacing of these molecules
这些分子的行间距
their individual weight
个体重量
the strength of the elastic bonds between them  and so on
它们之间弹性键的强度等等
gives this air mesh predictable behavior
使该气网具有可预测的行为
if you slam through these molecules faster
如果你能更快地穿过这些分子
than they can crash into themselves
比他们自己撞到自己还要多
you're exceeding the speed of sound
你已经超过音速了
on the ground
在地上
this happens at around seven hundred and sixty
这发生在大约七百六十岁
miles per hour in relatively normal conditions
在相对正常的情况下每小时英里
since they can't move out of the way fast enough
因为他们不能足够快地离开
air molecules bunch up when they hit
空气分子撞击时聚集在一起
parts of the plane that stick out
飞机突出的部分
forming shock waves that have predictable characteristics
形成具有可预测特征的冲击波
like angles that get sharper with increasing
比如随着增加而变得更锋利的角度
speed eighteen degrees to be precise at
准确地说是18度
Mach three point two cruising speed
3.2马赫巡航速度
let's throw a more standard wing into the mix
让我们在混音中加入一个更标准的翅膀
because these wings have much less sweepback angle
因为这些翅膀的后掠角要小得多
the nose shockwave blasts into them
鼻子冲击波冲进他们体内
causing a brick wall of drag to slow the plane down
造成一堵阻力砖墙使飞机减速
if you try to sweep them back far enough
如果你想把他们扫到足够远的地方
to tuck into the nose shock wave
塞进鼻子冲击波
the attachment point at the fuselage gets flimsy
机身的连接点变得脆弱
notice how the delta wing solves these issues
请注意三角翼如何解决这些问题
the classic aerodynamic wing profile shape is
经典的空气动力学机翼轮廓形状是
excellent for generating lift at slower speeds
非常适合在较慢的速度下产生升力
but as we approach supersonic speed
但当我们接近超音速时
its thickness and blunt leading edge cause air to bunch
它的厚度和钝的前缘导致空气聚集
up in front of the wing in a turbulent traffic jam
在混乱的交通堵塞中出现在机翼前
contributing to what's called the sound barrier
造成了所谓的音障
in contrast  as pressure builds with increasing speed
相比之下，随着压力的增加，速度也在增加
the SR71'S sharp
SR71很锋利
thin wing slices through the air
薄薄的翅膀在空中划过
the narrow leading edge allows the developing shock wave
狭窄的前缘允许发展中的冲击波
to eventually attach itself to the front of the wing
最终附着在机翼的前面
at the speed of sound and above
以音速及以上
the plane's sharp features comb air into smooth flowing
飞机的锋利特征将空气梳理成顺畅的流动
well behaved supersonic shock waves
表现良好的超音速冲击波
at leading and trailing edges
在前缘和后缘
the twin jet engines and their inlets are
双喷气发动机和它们的进气口
spaced out from the center to avoid air that
与中心隔开以避免空气
swirls up from under the fuselage
从机身下旋起
but are kept within the nose
但都藏在鼻子里
shockwave even at maximum speeds
冲击波即使在最高速度下
as we continue observing the exterior
随着我们继续观察外部
we see the characteristic ridges
我们看到特征性的脊
at each side of the fuselage
在机身两侧
in aerodynamic parlance
用空气动力学的说法
a sharp edge like this is called a chine
像这样锋利的边缘叫做中国
these chains serve a few critical tasks
这些链条服务于一些关键任务
they help form more powerful vortices as air
它们有助于形成更强大的漩涡作为空气
swirls up around them during flight
在飞行过程中在它们周围盘旋
which causes lower pressure above the sharp thin wings
这会导致锋利薄翼上方的压力降低
contributing to an impressive twenty
促成了令人印象深刻的二十年
percent of total lift at speed
速度总升力的百分比
they act like fins to stabilize the blackbird's
它们就像鳍一样稳定黑鸟的身体
long nose as it cuts through the air
长长的鼻子穿过空气
these chines also greatly reduce the radar cross section
这些中国也大大减少了雷达横截面
radar towers beam signals from a point outwards
雷达塔从一个点向外发射信号
common rounded plane features will reliably reflect some of
常见的圆形平面特征将可靠地反映一些
those waves back for easier identification from many angles
这些波浪更容易从多个角度识别
the blackbird's flatter surfaces reduce the
黑鸟扁平的表面减少了
likelihood of waves reflecting back to the source
波反射回震源的可能性
the rudders are also tilted or
方向舵也倾斜或
canted inwards for the same reason
出于同样的原因向内倾斜
its radar cross section makes it
它的雷达横截面使它
look much smaller than it is
看起来比它小得多
the sr-71 was among the first operational aircraft
sr-71是首批作战飞机之一
with this kind of intentional stealth shaping
用这种有意的隐形造型
the blackbird also featured an early radar
黑鸟还配备了早期雷达
absorbing composite material called plastic
吸收复合材料称为塑料
though not what we think of as plastic
虽然不是我们认为的塑料
composite wedges alternate with titanium along the
复合楔与钛沿
outer rim in a zigzag pattern to allow for expansion
锯齿形的外缘以允许扩展
this so called plastic also covers inlet cones and rudders
这种所谓的塑料也包括进气道锥和方向舵
the interior frame called the
内部框架称为
airframe is mostly made of titanium
机身主要由钛制成
as well as much of the exterior paneling for its
以及它的大部分外部镶板
performance under extreme stress and heat
极端应力和高温下的性能
some surfaces could reach seven hundred plus degrees
有些表面可以达到700多度
and the entire plane expanded several
整个飞机扩大了几个
inches when traveling at speed
高速行驶时的英寸
corrugations along the wing surface also allow
机翼表面的波纹也允许
expansion while contributing strength
扩张同时贡献力量
now that we've seen how the exterior shell and
现在我们已经看到了外壳和
underlying airframe are made for supersonic flight
下面的机身是为超音速飞行设计的
let's see how the engines get us there
看看引擎怎么带我们过去
we'll zoom in on just one side
我们只放大一边
there's the inlet spike at the front
前面有入口尖峰
which we'll get to in a bit
我们稍后会讨论这个问题。
the actual jet engine sits behind that and
真正的喷气发动机坐在后面
has a pretty standard overall design
具有相当标准的整体设计
air enters the jet engine and is forced backwards
空气进入喷气发动机被迫向后
by rotating disks with blades called rotors
通过用称为转子的叶片旋转圆盘
rings of stationary blades called stators make sure
称为定子的固定叶片环确保
the air flows generally backwards and builds
空气通常向后流动并形成
pressure instead of just twisting with the rotors
压力而不仅仅是旋转转子
the passage narrows
通道变窄了
compressing the air for more powerful combustion
压缩空气以获得更强大的燃烧
the compressed air now flows through separate nozzles
压缩空气现在通过单独的喷嘴流动
around a small outer ring
围绕一个小外环
while fuel is sprayed through the center
当燃料通过中心喷洒时
the fuel air mixture is ignited in many jet engines igniter
燃料空气混合物在许多喷气发动机点火器中被点燃
plugs not unlike a car spark plug are used but the sr 71 is
使用与汽车火花塞不同的插头，但sr 71是
different because of its special fuel that has its own
不同，因为它的特殊燃料有自己的
ignition requirements we'll look at that a little later
点火要求我们稍后再讲
once ignited
一旦点燃
the flame passes through small crossover
火焰通过小交叉
tubes until all burner cans are lit
直到所有燃烧器罐都点燃
the powerful exhaust shooting out of these
强大的排气喷出这些
cans pushes against turbines delivering
罐头推着交付的涡轮机
something like sixty thousand horsepower
大概六万马力
turbines are connected to internal gears and
涡轮机连接到内部齿轮和
shafts to drive those forward compressor rotors
驱动压缩机转子前进的轴
sucking in more air and continuing the cycle
吸入更多的空气继续循环
the exiting hot exhaust gas expands creating a fast
排出的热废气膨胀，形成快速
moving jet of air to push the plane forwards
推动飞机前进的气流
this setup with compressor
这个带压缩机的设置
combustor and turbine sections is
燃烧室和涡轮部分是
the basic turbojet engine design
基本涡喷发动机设计
animographics has a video about jet engines
动画学有一个关于喷气发动机的视频
if you want to see how this looks in a big
如果你想看看这个在大
airliner or a more modern fighter jet
客机或更现代的战斗机
high performance engines often have an afterburner section
高性能发动机通常有加力燃烧室部分
and the blackbird does as well
黑鸟也一样
fuel has been consumed
燃料已消耗
but there's still burnable air in
但里面还有可燃空气
the exiting exhaust stream
排出的废气流
additional fuel is sprayed into this stream
额外的燃料被喷到这条溪流中
the mixture wraps around v shaped
混合物包裹在v形周围
rings called flame holders
叫做火焰支架的戒指
which provide a contained area of
它提供了一个封闭的区域
turbulence for fuel mixing and combustion
燃料混合和燃烧的湍流
the mixture is ignited
混合物被点燃
for most applications
对于大多数应用程序
afterburner is fuel inefficient
加力燃烧室燃油效率低
but very powerful  as such
但本身就很强大
it's limited to short bursts
它仅限于短脉冲
in contrast
相比之下
the blackbird is designed to maintain continuous
黑鸟旨在保持连续
full afterburner at cruising speed for an hour or
以巡航速度全加力一小时或
so at a time between aerial refuelings
所以在空中加油之间的时间
all this heat and built up pressure must
所有这些热量和积聚的压力
now be converted into exhaust velocity
现在换算成排气速度
there's a special section here called
这里有一个特殊的部分叫做
a converging diverging nozzle
会聚发散喷嘴
hot  pressurized jet exhaust speeds up to
热加压喷射排气速度高达
squeeze through the narrow part
挤过狭窄的部分
and then expands through the wide exit
然后通过宽阔的出口扩张
converting all that heat and pressure into velocity
将所有的热量和压力转化为速度
there's a ring of flaps called the ejector that can
有一圈叫做弹射器的襟翼可以
alter the size of the exhaust opening for proper
改变排气口的大小以获得适当的
exhaust acceleration in varying conditions
不同条件下的排气加速度
accelerating exhaust is something like
加速排气就像
sticking your thumb over a garden hose
把你的拇指放在花园软管上
water still in the hose moves slowly and pushes
软管里的水缓慢移动并推动
harder against hose walls the more you block the
对软管墙越用力，你就越能阻挡
stream for a stronger spray at the end
最后流到更强的喷雾
in hard numbers
以硬数字
if air exiting the turbines is at Mach point four
如果涡轮机里的空气达到4马赫
air at the ejector flaps has accelerated to Mach
弹射襟翼处的空气加速到马赫数
three or more to match the plane's traveling speed
三个或更多以配合飞机的飞行速度
this late nineteen fifties fighter
这个五十年代末的战士
jet technology is awesome
喷气技术真棒
but it's not capable of sustaining
但它无法维持
Mach three point two on its own  in fact
3.2马赫，事实上。
the jet engine can't even use supersonic
喷气发动机甚至不能使用超音速
air as it would cause flame outs
空气会导致火焰熄灭
extinguishing the combustor among other things
除其他外，熄灭燃烧器
this is where the inlet spike comes into play
这就是入口尖峰发挥作用的地方
a supersonic shock wave forms at the sharp tip of the spike
超音速冲击波在尖峰尖端形成
tuning airflow for entry into the inlet chamber
调整进入入口室的气流
some compression is already
一些压缩已经
happening here outside of the nacelle
发生在机舱外面
just at the inlet lip
就在入口唇处
another shock wave forms
另一个冲击波形成
bounces or reflects a few times
反弹或反射几次
and eventually reaches the narrowest part of the
最终到达最狭窄的地方
inlet passage where its supersonic energy is finally
入口通道，它的超音速能量最终
converted having slowed to subsonic speeds
变慢到亚音速
the tremendous exchange of energy that happens as
巨大的能量交换发生在
supersonic air trades its velocity for increased pressure
超音速空气以其速度换取压力的增加
density and temperature is key
密度和温度是关键
you can't use supersonic air in the jet engine
你不能在喷气发动机中使用超音速空气
but you can use the jet engine like a pump to take in more
但是你可以用喷气发动机像泵一样吸收更多
and more supersonic air and convert it to pressure
和更多的超音速空气并将其转化为压力
it's the garden hose in reverse
这是反向的花园软管
if the fast water stream could be
如果快速的水流可以
crammed back into the hose
塞回水管里
to that end  there's an opening just before the inlet's
在入口前面有一个开口
narrowest point to bleed off some supersonic air
放出超音速空气的最窄点
it flows through shock traps to slow and pressure rise
它流过激波陷阱，减慢速度，压力上升
it surrounds and cools the engine
它包围并冷却发动机
and eventually rejoins the exhaust stream
并最终重新加入排气流
where it trades pressure for
它用压力来换取
velocity on its way out the back
从后面出来的速度
this process is so important that at
这个过程非常重要
Mach three point two cruise
3.2马赫巡航
just the pressure recovery alone from the inlet
仅从入口恢复压力
spike and bypass air is responsible for an
尖峰和旁路空气负责
incredible fifty eight percent of thrust
令人难以置信的58%的推力
this clever trick is also possible because there's
这个巧妙的技巧也是可能的，因为有
less air pressure at eighty thousand feet
八万英尺处气压更低
so you don't need to hold or build up as much pressure
所以你不需要保持或积累那么大的压力
inside the engine to release a super fast exhaust jet
在发动机内部释放出超快的排气射流
at sea level the air is much thicker
在海平面上，空气要厚得多
imagine that same garden hose but spraying underwater
想象一下同样的花园软管，但喷在水下
the spike is adjustable
尖峰是可调节的
with this much thrust coming from the
有这么大的推力来自
inlet spike at such high speeds
如此高速的进气尖峰
it's critical that shock waves maintain proper alignment
冲击波保持正确的排列是至关重要的
at Mach one point six
以1.6马赫的速度
the spike begins to retract and continues moving backwards
尖峰开始收缩并继续向后移动
to twenty six inches of rearward travel at its limit
在它的极限上向后移动26英寸
as speed hits Mach three point two
当速度达到3.2马赫时
the Blackbird's designed cruising speed
黑鸟设计的巡航速度
the inlet throat's shape changes as the spike moves
入口喉部的形状随着尖刺的移动而变化
at cruise  the spike shockwave sits right at the inlet lip
巡航时，尖峰冲击波正好位于入口边缘
again
再次
keeping this pre designed shockwave pattern is crucial
保持这种预先设计的冲击波模式至关重要
for example
例如
say some kind of internal error causes pressure
说某种内部错误导致压力
to build up at the mouth of the jet engine
在喷气发动机口堆积
pushing shock waves out of alignment
将冲击波推开
all that thrust is immediately lost
所有的推力都会立即消失
and the plane jerks abruptly to one side
飞机突然转向一边
slamming pilot's helmets against cockpit windows
把飞行员的头盔撞到驾驶舱窗户上
this is called an inlet unstart
这称为入口未启动
unstarts were harrowing experiences for
开始是痛苦的经历
sr-71 pilots with up to seventy percent of
SR-71飞行员拥有高达70%的
total thrust disappearing in an instant
总推力瞬间消失
if an unstart is detected
如果检测到未启动
the onboard computer moves the spike
机载计算机移动钉子
forward in an attempt to restart it
前进以尝试重新启动它
so that's it
所以就这样了
you've got the famed j fifty eight jet engines for
你有著名的J58喷气发动机
getting the blackbird off the ground and up to speed
让黑鸟离开地面并跟上速度
and the inlet spikes for comfortable
入口尖峰舒适
cruise well into the supersonic realm
巡航进入超音速领域
this system is so good at capturing the energy in
这个系统非常擅长捕捉
supersonic airflow that the black bird was known to
黑鸟已知的超音速气流
get better fuel mileage the faster it went
越快获得更好的燃油里程
now let's examine a few other components at the engine that
现在让我们检查一下发动机上的其他一些组件
help keep air flow in check at key points in the system
帮助控制系统关键点的气流
there are computer controlled forward bypass doors to let
有电脑控制的前门可以让
off excess air and keep inlet air pressure balanced
关闭多余的空气并保持入口空气压力平衡
however
然而
this slow air rejoining the outside flow could cause drag
这种缓慢的空气重新加入外部流动可能会导致阻力
there's another set of bypass doors just before the
前面还有一组旁路门
engine that the pilot can manually control which bleed
飞行员可以手动控制哪个出血的发动机
air into the nacelle bypass chamber instead
空气进入机舱旁路室
below马赫点5
there may not be enough airflow yet for proper cooling
可能还没有足够的气流来进行适当的冷却
there are suck in doors about halfway
大约一半的地方有门被吸进去了
down the nacelle that open to help out
打开来帮忙的机舱
there's a set of flaps at the back of the jet engine to
喷气发动机后面有一组襟翼
independently control afterburner exhaust pressure
独立控制加力燃烧室排气压力
and a ring of blown doors
和一圈被炸毁的门
to help keep the ejector area full at lower speeds and
以帮助在较低的速度下保持喷射器区域满
avoid dead spots which cause drag in the system
避免死点导致系统拖累
above Mach two point two there are six bypass tubes
2.2马赫以上有6个旁路管
that open to divert air from the jet engine's
打开以将空气从喷气发动机的
compressor section directly to the afterburner
压缩机部分直接到加力燃烧室
relieving internal engine pressure and
缓解发动机内部压力和
boosting afterburner performance
提高加力性能
up to forty percent of the engine intake volume can be
高达百分之四十的发动机进气量可以
bypassed in this way for a significant thrust increase
以这种方式绕过以获得显着的推力增加
the inlet spike has rows of small holes
入口尖峰有一排排小孔
and interior passages that take in cooling air at low speed
以及低速吸入冷却空气的内部通道
at higher speeds a thin layer of air builds up
在较高的速度下，一层薄薄的空气
around surfaces called the boundary layer
在称为边界层的表面周围
boundary layers can do weird things as the
边界层可以做奇怪的事情
air sticks to and follows the surface
空气附着并跟随表面
at curves air might separate and clog up the flow
在弯道处，空气可能会分离并堵塞流动
causing unwanted turbulence downstream
造成下游不必要的湍流
these holes bleed off boundary air
这些洞会排出边界空气
to keep flow running smoothly
保持流动顺畅
for weight reduction
为了减肥
there's no starter on the airplane
飞机上没有启动器
start carts were used with two muscle car engines placed
启动车与两个肌肉车发动机一起使用
side by side without mufflers running full blast
肩并肩，没有消声器全速运转
crew were said to enjoy the start
据说船员们喜欢开始
process for its impressive spectacle
其令人印象深刻的奇观的过程
a shaft with gears extends up and connects with the
带齿轮的轴向上延伸并与
gearbox at the underside of the jet engine to get
喷气发动机底部的变速箱
everything spinning and start the combustion process
一切都在旋转并开始燃烧过程
now let's move away from the engines
现在让我们离开引擎
for a look at the fuel system
看看燃料系统
as shown in the intro
如介绍所示
fuel tanks make up a large portion of the plane
油箱占了飞机的很大一部分
at takeoff  fuel flow rate could reach seventy four
起飞时燃油流量可达74
thousand pounds per hour for a single engine
单引擎每小时一千磅
that's about three gallons of fuel per second
大约是每秒三加仑燃料
or ten thousand eight hundred gallons per hour
或者每小时一万八百加仑
at Mach three point one five
以3.15马赫的速度
fuel flow is more efficient at a little
燃料流动效率更高
under three thousand gallons per hour
每小时三千加仑以下
the tank is incorporated into the wing structure
坦克并入机翼结构
without any additional bladder or barrier
没有任何额外的膀胱或屏障
since panels were designed to expand
由于面板旨在扩展
panel gaps meant fuel would leak from the plane when cold
面板间隙意味着冷时燃料会从飞机上泄漏
maintenance personnel had charts
维修人员有图表
for allowable drips per hour
每小时允许点滴
and when that rate was exceeded
当超过这个速度时
the plane's panels had to have sealant re applied
飞机的面板必须重新涂上密封剂
surfaces got so hot that normal fuel couldn't be used
表面变得如此之热以至于普通燃料无法使用
for risk of autoignition from surface heat alone
仅从表面热量就有自燃的危险
a special fuel called jp seven was developed
一种叫做jp7的特殊燃料被开发出来
which wouldn't spontaneously ignite below four
不会在四点以下自燃
hundred and sixty six degrees Fahrenheit
一百六十六华氏度
to ignite this fuel a special chemical was
为了点燃这种燃料，一种特殊的化学物质
required called triethylborane or teb for short
需要称为三乙基硼烷或简称teb
teb in contrast ignites on contact with air alone
相比之下，TEB仅与空气接触就会点燃
a shot of kerb was injected first to
首先注射了一针路缘
get the jp seven fuel burning
让jp 7燃料燃烧
which produced the famous green starting flame blast
产生了著名的绿色起爆火焰
additives in the fuel made it useful as a lubricant
燃料中的添加剂使其可用作润滑剂
coolant and hydraulic fluid
冷却液和液压油
it took on any of these roles throughout the plane
它在飞机上扮演着这些角色中的任何一个
especially in the engine's mechanical components
尤其是发动机的机械部件
the sr-71 had to be refueled shortly after takeoff because
sr-71不得不在起飞后不久加油，因为
the very heavy fuel load would stress the plane's landing
非常重的燃料负荷会给飞机的着陆带来压力
gear and require too much runway for lift off
需要太多的跑道才能起飞
among other limitations
除其他限制外
fueling normally happens at about
加油通常发生在大约
twenty five thousand feet
两万五千英尺
where the plane takes on an additional
飞机承担额外的
sixty thousand pounds of fuel
六万磅燃料
there are nitrogen containers in the front
前面有氮气容器
landing gear compartment to inert fuel tanks
起落架舱到惰性油箱
meaning air is allowed to vent out as nitrogen is pumped in
这意味着当氮气被泵入时，空气被允许排出
with no oxygen near the fuel
燃料附近没有氧气
it's considered inert or chemically inactive
它被认为是惰性的或化学不活跃的
greatly reducing explosion risk in
大大降低了爆炸风险
conditions of extreme pressure and heat
极压极热条件
flight control surfaces
飞行控制面
flight control surfaces are parts of an airplane's body
飞行控制面是飞机机身的一部分
that influence airflow to change the plane's attitude
影响气流改变飞机姿态
for example
例如
a fairly standard airplane has ailerons at each wingtip
标准的飞机在每个翼尖都有副翼
that move opposite one another to roll the plane
相对移动以滚动飞机
moving elevators at the tail affects pitch
移动尾部的电梯会影响音高
and the rudder controls yaw or rotation
方向舵控制偏航或旋转
about the airplane's vertical axis
关于飞机的垂直轴
the sr-71 has large dual rudders
SR-71有大的双舵
one above each engine
每个引擎上方一个
the Delta wing combines ailerons with elevators into
三角翼将副翼和升降机组合成
a single row of flaps that handles both tasks
处理这两个任务的单行襟翼
these are called elevons
这些被称为十一进制
each side moves as a single unit
每一边作为一个整体移动
opposite one another for roll
相对滚动
and together for pitch
一起投球
or some blended combination of both for maneuvers
或者两者的混合组合用于机动
that require some roll and pitch at the same time
同时需要一些滚动和俯仰
to achieve this blended mixed output
实现这种混合混合输出
there's a mechanical device in the
里面有一个机械装置
center tail section called a mixer
中心尾部称为混合器
cables from the flight stick in the cockpit pass
驾驶舱通行证上飞行棒上的电缆
through pulleys and tubes to arrive at the mixer
通过滑轮和管道到达搅拌机
there are separate down and back cable runs for stick
棍子有单独的向下和向后电缆运行
side to side or roll
左右滚动
and stick front to back or pitch
并从前到后或投球
at the mixer pitch cables connect to the pitch quadrant
在混音器处，间距电缆连接到间距象限
which is a partial wheel with channels and attach points
这是一个带有通道和连接点的部分轮子
roll cables attached to the roll quadrant behind that
卷缆连接到后面的卷象限
there's a mixed output bell crank at the front
前面有一个混合输出曲柄
with pushrods that link to the elevons at either side
推杆连接到两侧的电梯
roll input moves the entire bell crank left or right
滚动输入向左或向右移动整个钟形曲柄
because linkages are mirrored side to side
因为链接是左右镜像的
this ends up rotating elevons in opposite directions
这最终会使电梯向相反的方向旋转
pitch input rotates the bell crank itself
音高输入旋转钟形曲柄本身
which tilts elevons the same way on both sides
两边都以同样的方式倾斜
when pitch and roll commands happen together
当俯仰和滚动命令同时发生时
the bell crank gracefully blends these
曲柄优雅地混合了这些
commands for a singular output to each side
每边的奇异输出命令
this beautiful mechanical device is worth a closer look
这个漂亮的机械装置值得仔细看看
take the roll components for example
以轧辊组件为例
there's a feel spring that compresses to
有一个感觉弹簧可以压缩到
give the pilot felt feedback in the stick
在操纵杆上给飞行员感觉反馈
for the position of parts in the system
用于系统中零件的位置
because as we'll see in a minute
因为我们一会儿就会看到
the ailerons themselves are hydraulically controlled
副翼本身是液压控制的
there's no direct mechanical connection
没有直接的机械连接
moving down the chain
向下移动
there's a trim actuator
有一个修剪执行器
trim adds more permanent adjustment to the
Trim为
system so the pilot doesn't have to hold the
这样飞行员就不用拿着
stick in one place for long periods of time
长时间呆在一个地方
for example to fight against a continuous side wind
例如对抗持续的侧风
the system still allows moment to moment
系统仍然允许时刻
input on top of the trim setting
修剪设置顶部的输入
the pilot controls the trim level from the cockpit
飞行员从驾驶舱控制配平
pitch components also have these parts
音高组件也有这些部分
the pitch feel spring is at the bottom of the mixer
音高感觉弹簧在搅拌机的底部
the pitch trim actuator is at the back
俯仰修剪执行器在后面
now watch as the bell crank executes blended roll and
现在看着钟形曲柄执行混合辊和
pitch commands with accompanying trim settings
带有附带修剪设置的音高命令
also connected to the pitch system there's a stick
还有一根棍子连接到音高系统
pusher with its own computer controlled actuator
具有自己的计算机控制执行器的推进器
the stick pusher can shake the stick as a warning
推棒器可以摇动棍子作为警告
or automatically push the stick
或者自动推棍子
forward to avoid or counterstall
向前以避免或阻止
stalls can happen for example if the plane exceeds
例如，如果飞机超过
certain flight angle limits interrupting lift and
某些飞行角度限制中断升力和
causing the plane to fall through the air
导致飞机从空中坠落
from the mixer
从搅拌机
rods at each side translate
每边的杆平移
movements to individual servo units
移动到单个伺服单元
the servo converts this physical movement into hydraulic
伺服系统将这种物理运动转化为液压运动
pressure to regulate rows of actuators at each aileron
调节每个副翼上执行器排的压力
it has a sensing rod to monitor aileron position
它有一个感应杆来监控副翼位置
from this inboard servo a train of rods and
从这个内侧伺服系统一列杆和
linkages continues to an outboard servo
连杆继续到舷外伺服
which controls another set of actuators
控制另一组执行器
there's a separate set of cables
有一套单独的电缆
pulleys and hydraulic components for each rudder
每个舵的滑轮和液压元件
a rotating post with an attached actuator extends
带有附加执行器的旋转柱延伸
from the rudder stub into the rudder frame
从舵柱到舵架
landing gear
起落架
there's a single steerable nose wheel at the front
前面有一个可操纵的前轮
and twin gear at the back
后面有双齿轮
the peculiar light grey rear tires are made of rubber
奇特的浅灰色后轮胎由橡胶制成
infused with aluminum powder for a much higher flash point
注入铝粉以获得更高的闪点
that is the temperature at which they could catch fire
这是它们可能着火的温度
they're pressurized to an unbelievable four hundred psi
它们被加压到难以置信的400磅/平方英寸
your average car tire sits at
你的普通汽车轮胎
around thirty to thirty five psi
大约30到35 psi
they are also inflated with nitrogen
它们也充入了氮气
instead of oxygen for fire resistance
代替氧气防火
the Blackbird's aerodynamic qualities
黑鸟的空气动力学特性
mean higher landing speeds overall
总体平均着陆速度更高
to further slow the plane down and
进一步减慢飞机的速度
take stress off the wheels
减轻车轮的压力
there's a forty foot diameter drag shoot
有一个直径40英尺的拖曳射击
which is deployed at main gear touchdown at
它部署在主齿轮触地处
about one hundred and fifty knots airspeed
大约一百五十节空速
now let's head to the front of the plane for a
现在让我们去飞机前面
look inside the blackbird's dual cockpits
看看黑鸟的双座舱内部
the pilot sits in the forward cockpit to
飞行员坐在前面的驾驶舱里
fly the plane among other duties
驾驶飞机
with the reconnaissance systems officer or rso in
侦察系统官员或rso在
the rear cockpit to run onboard equipment and
后驾驶舱运行机载设备和
direct navigation along the mission flight path
沿任务飞行路线直接导航
moving to the pilot's position
移动到飞行员的位置
let's get into the instruments and controls
让我们进入仪器和控制
front and center there's a grouping
前面和中间有一个分组
of main flight instruments
主要飞行仪表
the attitude indicator shows the plane's
姿态指示器显示飞机的
position relative to the horizon
相对于地平线的位置
with a backup attitude indicator nearby for redundancy
附近有备用姿态指示器以备冗余
below that the HSI or horizontal situation indicator
低于HSI或水平情况指标
shows the plane's position relative to a heading or
显示飞机相对于航向或
preset point in space and the plane's relationship to the
空间中的预设点和平面与
imaginary line from one heading to the next including
从一个航向到下一个航向的虚线，包括
remaining distance side to side deviation and so on
剩余距离左右偏差等
below that a map projector which ran on sixteen
在那下面是一台地图投影仪，它运行在16号
millimeter film and contains the entire flight route
毫米胶片，包含整个飞行路线
there are a few instruments here which
这里有一些仪器
are standard to most airplane
是大多数飞机的标准
the altimeter for altitude
高度表
airspeed for general forward speed in knots and vertical
空速，用于以节和垂直为单位的一般前进速度
airspeed for how fast the plane is moving up or down
空速表示飞机上升或下降的速度
at supersonic speeds and very high altitudes
以超音速和极高的高度
outside air conditions and supersonic airflow around the
外部空气条件和周围的超音速气流
plane's exterior components affects instrument accuracy
飞机外部部件影响仪器精度
as such  sr-71 pilots relied on the triple
因此sr-71飞行员依赖于三重
display indicator at speed
速度显示指示器
there's the kts indicator at the top for knots equivalent
顶部有kts指示器，用于结等效
airspeed which takes into account air compressibility at
考虑空气压缩率的空速
high altitude for an adjusted speed calculation
用于调整速度计算的高海拔
for reference
供参考
there could be up to one hundred knots difference between
两者之间可能有100海里的差距
the normal airspeed indicator and this adjusted reading
正常空速指示器和这个调整后的读数
altitude is beneath that
海拔低于那个
and mock at the bottom
并在底部模拟
down and to the right there are fuel flow gauges
下面和右边是燃油流量计
measured in thousands of pounds per hour
以每小时数千磅计算
oil pressure gauges are nearby
油压力表就在附近
there are gauges for hydraulic pressure in various systems
各种系统中都有液压压力表
above that a grouping of instruments related
上面是一组相关的文书
to exhaust including exhaust nozzle position
到排气，包括排气喷嘴位置
indicators and exhaust temperature
指标和排气温度
normal running temperature is eight hundred degrees
正常运行温度是八百度
Fahrenheit and can be manually adjusted or trimmed by the
华氏温度，可手动调整或修剪
pilot  there are fire warning lights nearby
飞行员附近有火警灯
and tachometers to measure engine rotation speed
和转速计来测量发动机转速
idle is about thirty nine hundred rpm while
空闲时间约为3900转/分，而
cruise is around seven thousand one hundred rpm
巡航大约是七千一百转
that's not much difference in engine rotation speed for
发动机转速相差不大
all the action happening in that part of the plane
飞机那一部分发生的所有动作
there's an elapsed time gauge which is a sort of
有一个经过的时间计，这是一种
stopwatch rarely used but a government requirement
秒表很少使用，但政府要求
moving leftward there's the angle of attack indicator to
向左移动有迎角指示器
track the plane's angle relative to its direction of travel
跟踪飞机相对于行驶方向的角度
you'll recall from earlier the plane is designed to
你会记得早些时候飞机被设计成
sit at about six degrees angle of attack at cruise
在巡航时以大约6度的迎角坐着
there are gauges
有仪表
switches and lights related to the previously shown inlets
与前面显示的入口相关的开关和灯
spikes and engines
尖峰和引擎
for most of the flight
在飞行的大部分时间里
the inlets are automatically
入口是自动的
controlled by onboard computers
由机载计算机控制
but the pilot can take manual control if needed
但如果需要飞行员可以手动控制
there are left and right inlet unstart warning lights
有左右入口不启动警示灯
with restart switches at the bottom left
左下角有重启开关
there's a spike position gauge with
有一个尖峰位置计
two indicators one for each side
两个指示器，每边一个
and position switches
和位置开关
compressor inlet temperature and pressure gauges
压缩机入口温度和压力表
to monitor conditions at the compressor face or
监测压缩机表面的状况或
front of the j fifty eight jet engine
j58喷气发动机前
with a pair of switches for air
带一对空气开关
bypass control in this area
该区域的旁路控制
there's a stick pusher or shaker switch to the left
左边有一个推杆或摇杆开关
when turned on
打开时
the stick will shake if the pilot is
如果飞行员是，棍子会摇晃
approaching angle of attack limits
接近迎角极限
and forcefully push the stick forward
并用力将棍子向前推
if the pilot ignores the shaking
如果飞行员无视震动
the rso bailout switch is used to request bailout
rso救助开关用于请求救助
since the rso or backseat officer should go first
因为rso或后座警官应该先走
in emergency bailout conditions to avoid safety
在紧急救助条件下避免安全
concerns with opening canopies and so on
对开启檐篷等的担忧
the rso ejected light indicates if
rso射出的光指示是否
the rso has actually ejected
rso实际上已经弹出
these are failsafes if the communication
这些是故障保险，如果通信
system between officers isn't working
警官之间的系统不起作用
the drag shoot pull handle is up and to the left
拖射拉手向上向左
at the bottom there are indicator gauges for pitch
底部有音高指示器
roll and yaw trim levels
滚动和偏航修剪水平
the roll trim switch is at the left side of the cockpit
滚动装饰开关在驾驶舱左侧
a combined pitch and yaw trim switch
组合俯仰和偏航配平开关
is located on the flight stick
位于飞行棒上
with left to right for yaw and up and down for pitch
从左到右代表偏航，上下代表俯仰
while we're at the stick
当我们在棍子上的时候
let's review other controls here
让我们在这里回顾一下其他控件
there's a button to switch the pilot's microphone
有一个按钮可以切换飞行员的麦克风
between internal or external communication
内部或外部沟通之间
the dual purpose button on the right either
右边的两用按钮
activates control stick command so the pilot can
激活控制杆命令，以便飞行员可以
use the stick during autopilot or it can activate
在自动驾驶期间使用棍子，或者它可以激活
nose wheel steering when on the ground
在地面上时前轮转向
a button towards the front turns on the rain removal system
前面的按钮打开防雨系统
and a multipurpose trigger at the front can control
前面的多功能触发器可以控制
things like disconnecting air refueling components
比如断开空中加油组件
interrupting pitch or yaw trim  and more
中断俯仰或偏航修剪等
while in flight
飞行中
the rudder pedals at each side control rudder
两侧的舵踏板控制方向舵
angle when pressed inwards from the bottom
从底部向内按压时的角度
moving feet up to rotate the pedals controls wheel
向上移动脚以旋转踏板控制车轮
braking for each side while on the ground
在地面上两边都要刹车
moving now to the right or starboard side of the cockpit
现在向驾驶舱右侧或右舷移动
there are instruments related to fuel management
有与燃料管理相关的工具
balancing the massive fuel load front to
平衡大量的燃料负荷
back greatly affects performance
背部极大地影响性能
since the plane  again
自从飞机又来了
is designed to sit at a particular angle
被设计成以特定的角度坐着
there's a main fuel level gauge in pounds
有一个以磅为单位的主燃料液位计
beneath that the center of gravity indicator
下面是重心指示器
the fuel system draws from
燃料系统从
forward tanks and works backwards
向前坦克，向后工作
so the center of gravity will move aft as fuel is consumed
所以重心会随着燃料消耗而向船尾移动
at speed  this center of gravity has shifted
这个重心的移动速度
twenty five percent towards the back
百分之二十五朝后面
there's a fuel forward transfer switch that moves
有一个燃料正向转换开关可以移动
fuel back into forward tanks when switched on
开机后将燃料倒入前进油箱
and a corresponding fuel aft transfer switch which
以及相应的燃料尾部转换开关
moves fuel rearward and must be held down to operate
将燃料向后移动，必须按住才能操作
there's a fuel tank pressure gauge at the bottom and gauges
底部有一个油箱压力表和仪表
to measure nitrogen quantity in various tanks which is used
测量使用的各种罐中的氮量
for inerting as we saw in the fuel system explanation
就像我们在燃料系统解释中看到的那样
there's a fuel dump switch to quickly
有一个快速加油开关
dump thousands of pounds of fuel
倾倒数千磅燃料
for example to drop weight in an emergency situation
例如在紧急情况下减肥
emergency fuel shut off switches are nearby
紧急燃料关闭开关就在附近
now let's head over to the left or port side of the cockpit
现在我们去驾驶舱左边或者左舷
there's a grouping of dials for environmental
这里有一组关于环境的表盘
controls such as cockpit temperature  face heat
驾驶舱温度面热等控制
and suit heat
和西装热
which control heating in the pilot's helmet and suit
控制飞行员头盔和防护服的加热
and a nearby temperature gauge with a switch
和附近带开关的温度计
to select which system it should display
选择它应该显示的系统
near the bottom there's a cabin altitude gauge
底部附近有一个船舱高度计
crew could choose cabin pressurization equivalent
机组人员可以选择客舱增压当量
to ten thousand or twenty six thousand feet
到一万或二万六千英尺
and a Liquid oxygen level indicator beneath
和下面的液氧水平指示器
Liquid oxygen is converted to gas and pumped
液氧被转化为气体并被泵送
into the crew's helmets for breathing
进入船员的头盔呼吸
the landing gear lever is nearby
起落架杆就在附近
with associated indicator lights
带有相关的指示灯
switches and so on
开关等
as we pivot all the way to the left side wall
当我们转向左边的墙
we see the dual throttle levers
我们看到双油门杆
there's a button here to toggle the pilot's microphone
这里有一个按钮可以切换飞行员的麦克风
and a switch beneath that to manually
下面有一个手动开关
initiate the inlet spike restart sequence
启动入口尖峰重启序列
each throttle channel has a tab counter to
每个节气门通道都有一个标签计数器
track how many shots of tab are used from a
跟踪从一个
starting total of sixteen shots per side
每边总共16次投篮
for example
例如
the throttles move forward up to a limit
油门向前移动到一个极限
which corresponds to normal engine power
这对应于正常的发动机功率
the pilot must lift the throttles up over
飞行员必须把油门抬起来
this detent to engage afterburners
这个棘爪用于接合加力燃烧室
doing so fires a shot of teb to start the afterburners
这样做会发射一枪teb来启动加力燃烧室
and the counters tick down each time this happens
每次发生这种情况时，计数器都会滴答作响
afterburner power is controllable from
加力功率可从
min to max along the stick travel
沿着棍子行程的最小到最大值
there's an oxygen settings control panel behind that
后面有一个氧气设置控制面板
a nearby pull handle will jetison the canopy
附近的拉手会破坏天篷
other panels here include a radio panel
这里的其他面板包括无线电面板
standby oxygen panel
备用氧气板
a panel for various lights such as landing gear lights
起落架灯等各种灯的面板
and more  controls for the map projector are found
并找到地图投影仪的更多控件
towards the front of this panel area
朝向这个面板区域的前面
corresponding banks of controls on the starboard
右舷相应的控制台
side handle things like internal comms system
侧面处理内部通信系统之类的东西
computer navigation aids for flying
用于飞行的计算机导航设备
landing and takeoff
着陆和起飞
autopilot and more
自动驾驶仪等
the rear cockpit echoes many of the same gauges
后驾驶舱与许多相同的仪表相呼应
switches and indicators with some crucial additions
带有一些关键附加功能的开关和指示器
there's a viewside monitor which lets the rso see directly
有一个视场监视器可以让rso直接看到
beneath the plane with magnification settings and more
具有放大倍率设置等的平面下方
a radar display sits beneath that
雷达显示器位于其下方
and a large map projector plane
和一个大型地图投影仪飞机
there's a control panel for the
有一个控制面板
astro inertial navigation device
天文惯性导航装置
which we'll cover in a bit
我们稍后会介绍。
there's a panel with controls and
有一个控制面板和
indicators for reconnaissance equipment
侦察设备指示器
controls at the left side include a def panel to engage
左侧的控件包括一个要接合的def面板
onboard defensive systems which could counter any threats
机载防御系统，可以对抗任何威胁
to the plane from things like surface to air missiles
从地对空导弹到飞机
air to air missiles
空对空导弹
hostile fighter intercept attempts  and so on
敌方战斗机拦截企图等等
there are also radio and intercom controls in this area
这个区域还有无线电和对讲机控制
as we move away from the controls
当我们离开控制
we can take in other items in these cockpits
我们可以在这些驾驶舱里收纳其他物品
the rso has retractable sun shades
rso有可伸缩的太阳镜
the pilot has a positionable sun visor with Wings
飞行员有一个带翅膀的可定位遮阳板
sun glare at altitude could make instrument
高空的太阳眩光可能会使仪器
visibility almost impossible if not blocked
如果不被封锁，能见度几乎是不可能的
both cockpits have small mirrors to help crew see
两个驾驶舱都有小镜子，可以帮助船员看到
themselves due to the difficulty of some actions in
由于某些行动的困难
their bulky flight suits in confined quarters
他们笨重的飞行服在狭小的空间里
the pilot has a retractable periscope to view the
飞行员有一个可伸缩的潜望镜来查看
plane looking aft for things like engine fires
飞机在尾部寻找引擎起火之类的东西
contrailing
尾迹
fuel dumping
燃料倾倒
and to check rudder position
并检查方向舵位置
windows have inner and outer panes with an air gap
窗户有带气隙的内外窗格
glass at the outside reaches temperatures of four
外面的玻璃温度达到4度
to five hundred degrees Fahrenheit at cruise
到华氏五百度
with the interior panes surface in the
内部窗格表面在
two hundred and fifty degree range
二百五十度范围
the cockpit had to have air pumped in at negative forty
驾驶舱必须在零下40度注入空气
degrees to keep interior temps at a comfortable sixty
将室内温度保持在舒适的60度
degrees for crew who wore their own climate controlled
穿着自己气候控制的船员的学位
flight suits
飞行服
the suits themselves have various critical layers
西装本身有各种临界层
starting with a thin nylon comfort layer against the skin
从贴在皮肤上的薄尼龙舒适层开始
followed by an inflatable rubber bladder layer
然后是充气橡胶囊层
for added warmth against cold air or water in the
以增加对冷空气或水的温暖
event of emergency exit from the cockpit
紧急情况下离开驾驶舱
a fishnet type layer helps the suit
渔网型层有助于西装
keep its proper shape when inflated
充气时保持其应有的形状
and the iconic orange outer layer which is fire
标志性的橙色外层是火
resistant up to eight hundred degrees Fahrenheit
可抵抗800华氏度
there are metal rings for glove and helmet attach points
有手套和头盔连接点的金属环
and connections for climate and breathing air
以及气候和呼吸空气的联系
there are easily accessible leg zipper pockets
有容易接近的腿拉链口袋
velcro pads just above the knees for
尼龙搭扣垫就在膝盖以上
sticking important documents
粘贴重要文件
the helmet has a face shield with a sun visor
头盔有一个带遮阳板的面罩
and a feeding port for squeezing food out of tubes
和一个从管子里挤出食物的进料口
there's a neoprene seal around the face to allow
面部周围有氯丁橡胶密封
pressurization to sea level for comfortable breathing
加压至海平面，呼吸舒适
where the rest of the suit matches cockpit pressure levels
其余部分与驾驶舱压力水平相匹配
the seat has a parachute in the headrest
座位头枕上有降落伞
and is anchored to a support rack upon which
并锚定在支撑架上
it slides during the ejection process
它在弹出过程中滑动
there are cables at the bottom for attachment to
底部有电缆用于连接
metal brackets at the heel of each boot
每个靴子后跟的金属支架
these cables pull the pilot's feet tight to the
这些缆绳把飞行员的脚拉紧
seat frame during ejection to avoid striking
弹射时的座椅框架以避免撞击
limbs as the seat blasts out of the cockpit
四肢随着座椅冲出驾驶舱
equipment the nose and side bays at the front of
装备前面的鼻子和侧舱
the plane have components for both airplane
这架飞机有两架飞机的组件
functionality and mission specific objectives
功能和特定任务目标
i'll show you the zoomed in individual units
我将向您展示放大后的单个单位
and then we'll zoom out
然后我们会缩小
so you can see their range and capabilities from
所以你可以从
eighty thousand feet down to the earth's surface
八万英尺下到地表
the pitot mast is a thin tube with various probes
皮托管是一根带有各种探针的细管
which feeds air pressure data to onboard computers
它将气压数据输入机载计算机
and instruments for things like airspeed
以及诸如空速之类的仪器
angle of attack  and more
攻角等等
the entire nose section is interchangeable and can be
整个鼻子部分是可互换的，可以
swapped out between flights to suit mission objectives
在不同航班之间调换以适应任务目标
there are three noses
有三个鼻子
two with different radar types
两个有不同的雷达类型
and an optical bar camera which i featured here
和我在这里展示的光学条形相机
the Optical bar camera had film reels that carried ten
光学棒相机有10个胶卷
thousand five hundred feet of five inch wide film
一千五百英尺五英寸宽的胶片
for comparison
用于比较
a normal ninety minute movie would use eight thousand
一部正常的九十分钟电影需要八千美元
one hundred feet of thirty five millimeter film
一百英尺的三十五毫米胶卷
it could also film in stereo vision to
它也可以用立体视觉拍摄
help identify objectives easier
帮助更轻松地确定目标
moving aft there are liquid oxygen supply bottles
船尾有液氧供应瓶
there are bays which house components for
有隔间容纳组件
the sr seven one's defensive systems
sr 7one的防御系统
further AFT there's a Bay with Radar recording equipment
再往前走，有一个装有雷达记录设备的海湾
the Blackbird's unusual speed and altitude tended to
黑鸟不同寻常的速度和高度
activate hostile Radar and missile systems along its flight
启动敌方的雷达和导弹系统
path  these signals could be captured and analyzed
可以捕获和分析这些信号的路径
to better understand their capabilities
更好地了解他们的能力
the bays behind that hold technical objective cameras for
后面的隔间有技术目标摄像机
more detailed photography of smaller specific areas
更详细地拍摄更小的特定区域
just behind the rear cockpit
就在后驾驶舱后面
there's the astroinertial navigation system or
有天体惯性导航系统或
ans to precisely monitor airplane location
ANS精确监控飞机位置
it would track three star groups within
它能追踪三个星团
thirty seconds after leaving the hanger
离开衣架30秒后
no matter the time of day
无论一天中的什么时候
the sr-71's location could be pinpointed to
SR-71的位置可以精确定位到
within three hundred feet anywhere in the world
世界上任何地方三百英尺之内
even at马赫speeds
this was well before the existence of gps satellites
这是早在gps卫星出现之前
also in these bays and compartments there are batteries
在这些海湾和隔间中还有电池
radio equipment
无线电设备
antennas and computers that run or assist
运行或协助的天线和计算机
other components related to mission goals
与任务目标有关的其他组成部分
airplane function and more
飞机功能等
and here's a zoomed out diagram to
这是一个缩小的图表
show you what each component sees
向您展示每个组件看到的内容
the optical bar camera can continuously photograph an
光条相机可以连续拍摄
eighty two mile wide by two point three miles long patch
82英里宽2.3英里长
radar can monitor an eleven mile area from twenty three to
雷达可以监测从23到11英里的区域
one hundred and fifteen miles from the flight path
距离飞行路线一百一十五英里
signal repeaters can see from horizon to horizon
信号中继器可以从一个地平线看到另一个地平线
technical objective cameras locate and photograph
技术物镜相机定位和拍照
hundreds of targets to within six inches of
数百个目标在六英寸内
resolution within a sixteen mile range side to side
16英里范围内的分辨率
perhaps what makes the SR71 so special is its rarity
也许SR71之所以如此特别是因为它的稀有性
to have the right people and talents come together
让合适的人和人才走到一起
with proper funding and be allowed to flex their
有适当的资金，并被允许弯曲他们的
talents fully is apparently a very rare thing indeed
完全的天赋显然是一件非常罕见的事情
and often results in legends that persist
并经常导致传说持续存在
hey everyone  Jake here
嘿各位Jake在这里
creator vanamagraphs
创作者vanamagraph
first of all
首先
thanks for being on the channel and enjoying my work
感谢您在频道上并享受我的工作
this project was awesome to create
这个项目创建起来很棒。
and i'm going to be releasing a behind the scenes video
我将发布一段幕后视频
shortly after the release of this one detailing everything
在这个详细说明一切的版本发布后不久
that went into making this project from the research that i
从我的研究中进入这个项目
had to find and dig deep to get to crafting the model
必须找到并深入挖掘才能制作模型
and doing the materials and rendering and the rigs
做材料、渲染和钻机
so building the moving mechanical objects
所以建造移动的机械物体
the items in these projects many of them
这些项目中的项目很多
actually work how they would in real life
实际上他们在现实生活中的工作方式
these are real recreations
这些都是真正的娱乐
and i want to show you how i do it and bring you into the
我想向你展示我是如何做到的，并带你进入
magic and the madness of making animographs and i promise i'll
魔法和制作动画片的疯狂，我保证我会
be entertaining and i might even tell a few light jokes here
很有趣，我甚至可能在这里讲一些轻松的笑话
and there so something to look forward to anyway later
反正以后也有值得期待的事情